Guide to the Bella C. Landauer Collection of Business and Advertising Ephemera 1700-1990 PR 31
New-York Historical Society
Bella C. Landauer Collection of Business and Advertising Ephemera
1700-1990
New-York Historical Society
PR 31
150.00 Linear feet (ca. 800,000 items)
Collection of mainly 19th and 20th century advertising ephemera. Formats in the collection include American trade cards, lottery tickets, handbills, labels, broadsides, calendars, billheads, price lists, advertising fans, and other materials of history and popular culture. Media range from rough woodcuts to chromolithographs.
Provenance
Gift of Bella C. Landauer between 1926 and 1960, with later additions by her son, James D. Landauer. Other advertising ephemera by a variety of donors, as well as material with no attributed provenance, were added to the collection after Landauer's death.
Access Restrictions
Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Open to qualified researchers by advance appointment only. To schedule an appointment, contact the Print Room Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. See guidelines in Print Room for details.
Biographical Note
Bella Landauer was born Bella Clara Fackenthal in New York in 1874, the only child of a prosperous corset manufacturer. She attended classes at Miss Hewitt's, and became proficient in several foreign languages. Her father disapproved of college for women, so Bella educated herself with her inquiring mind and interest in many different subjects, including opera and theater. In 1900 she married Ian Nathan Landauer, a fabric importer and salesman, and a first-generation immigrant from Germany. The Landauers' sons were born in 1902 and 1906, and Bella devoted her intense energy to the task wife and motherhood. During World War I Mrs. Landauer volunteered for the New York chapter of the American Volunteer Field Service, which took a toll on her health. A doctor ordered her to rest, and Landauer looked to find more suitable activities for herself.
Bella Landauer first began collecting ephemera in 1923, when she bought a portfolio of bookplates and other prints for one hundred dollars. Though that portfolio was later revealed to have been stolen from a dealer, Landauer was permanently hooked on the idea of collecting printed ephemera. She first embarked on a quest to discover and acquire new bookplates. The next year she added tradecards. Subsequently, as she encountered new genres of material, her interests expanded and her collections grew. She traveled to Europe in search of ephemera, and began to create special collections on specific advertising themes.
In 1926, when Landauer moved from her brownstone at 11 West 74th Street into an apartment in the Drake Hotel, she no longer had space to house her already quite large collection of ephemera. She offered part of her collection to the New-York Historical Society, initially presenting a group of trade cards and bookplates, but never stopped adding to and expanding the collection. Landauer was first given a former kitchen in which to store and organize her collections. However, when the Society's building was expanded in the late 1930s, a special room was created on the third floor to house the Landauer Collection.
Landauer was made an Honorary Curator of the collection but was never on the Society's payroll. She spent hours at the Society organizing her various materials, and members of the public were invited to view them on Sunday afternoons. Landauer continued to collect and donate items, including lottery tickets, posters, sheet music, cameo cards, and matchbooks, until her death in 1960. Her son James D. Landauer donated more items to her collections.
Landauer often referred to her collections as "scraps of old paper," but these ephemeral items have proven to be valuable graphic records of their times. The New-York Historical Society's Bella C. Landauer Collection of Business and Advertising Ephemera holds over eight hundred thousand items. Landauer also donated ephemera to many other institutions: The Metropolitan Museum of Art, the Smithsonian Institution, the New York Public Library, Dartmouth College library, Library of Congress, and Baker Library at Harvard University.
In 2001, Landauer's reference materials were separated from the ephemera collection material, and became a separate collection, the Bella C. Landauer Reference and Writings Collection (PR 149.) All three-dimensional items (such as milk cartons, matchbooks, and paperweights) were transferred to the New-York Historical Society's Department of Painting, Sculpture, and Decorative Arts.
Related Materials at the New-York Historical Society
Bella C. Landauer Writings and Reference Collection PR 149 contains scrapbooks, indices, monographs, articles, and correspondence which comprise an archive for the Bella C. Landauer Collection of Business and Advertising Ephemera at the New-York Historical Society, as well as for other collections of Landauer's that she deposited at other institutions.
Additional advertisements and ephemera are held in the Ephemera File, PR 264.
Additional materials donated by Bella Landauer are held in the library's general collections and in the museum collections.
Scope and Content Note
The Bella C. Landauer Collection of Business and Advertising Ephemera contains material spanning the nineteenth and twentieth centuries. The Collection contains an amazing array of advertising ephemera in a variety of formats: posters, trade cards, cigar labels, product labels, printed advertisements, and sheet music, among others. The collection was originally organized by Landauer, as described above, in a variety of ways, most usually by format or by product being advertised.
Landauer's own lists of items by subject can be found in the Bella C. Landauer Reference and Writings Collection (PR 149).
Throughout Series I and II, all ephemera is organized by the product for which it is advertising. This makes searching for specific businesses and industries easy, but searching for examples of specific printers or lithographers more difficult. Researchers are encouraged to contact the Print Room reference staff at printroom@nyhistory.org for assistance.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into 8 series:
Series:
Series I. Scrapbooks
Series II. Ephemera Files (small, medium, large)
Series III. Sheet Music
Series IV. Weichsel Tobacco Collection
Series V. Photographs and Fine Art Works
Series VI. Playing Cards
Series VII: Speakeasy Cards
Series VIII: World War II Army-Navy "E" Awards Ephemera
Clubs -- New York (State) -- New York.; Slavery -- United States.; Cryptography -- United States.; Asbestos -- United States.; Theater -- United States.; Dry-goods -- United States.; Transportation -- United States.; Tobacco -- United States.; Beverages -- United States.; Patent medicines -- United States.; Clothing and dress -- United States.; Advertising -- United States.; Scrapbooks.; Prohibition -- New York (State) -- New York.; Electricity; Penmanship; Cigars; Dance -- United States.; Women -- Suffrage -- United States.; Posters.; New York (N.Y.) -- Description and travel.; Advertisements.; Trade cards.; Lottery ticket.; Handbills; Food -- United States.; Price lists; Billheads; Calendars.; Cigarette package labels; Cigar box labels; Bookmarks; Sheet music.; Broadsides (notices); Prints (visual works).; Labels (identifying artifacts)
- Series I: SCRAPBOOKS
  Scope and Contents note
  Once she moved her collection to the New-York Historical Society, Landauer had the Society's bindery create large scrapbooks for her, which she filled with small ephemera, organized by the kind of product being advertised. Within the scrapbooks, there is rarely any further refinement of organization; a researcher looking for a specific business or product may need to consult each of the 4 or 5 scrapbooks compiled on the subject in order to complete an exhaustive search. In some cases, Landauer's own lists (in PR 149) may be of use, but so much of the material has been moved around since Landauer's time that those lists may not be of more help than exhaustively searching.
  In addition to the scrapbooks she compiled, filled with pasted and taped-in small paper ephemera, Landauer collected scrapbooks that had been compiled by others. These are of various sizes and subjects and are filed at the end of the series, with brief descriptions found in the box and folder list. Some additional scrapbooks of ephemera, acquired by the N-YHS after Landauer's death, have been added to this set.
  The following is a list of subject headings, under which material is filed. Each topic may have several scrapbooks.
  - ADVERTISING
    - BCL Vol.1 (Offsite-box SB 1, Folder 1-3)
    - BCL Vol. 1 (Offsite-box SB 2, Folder 4-6)
  - AGRICULTURE
    - BCL Vol. 01 D (Offsite-box SB 3, Folder 1-5)
    - BCL Vol. 01 E (Offsite-box SB 4, Folder 6-9)
  - ANIMALS
    - BCL Vol. 01 A (Offsite-box SB 5, Folder 1-5)
    - BCL Vol. 01 A (Offsite-box SB 6, Folder 6-7)
    - BCL Vol. 01 B (Offsite-box SB 7, Folder 8-9)
  - ANTIQUES
    - BCL Vol. 01 C (Offsite-box SB 8, Folder 1-4)
  - ART (including libraries, all museums, and autographs)
    - BCL Vol. 01 C-1/2 (Offsite-box SB 9, Folder 1-3)
  - BEVERAGES
    - BCL vol. 02 A (Offsite-box SB 10, Folder 1-4)
    - BCL Vol. 02 A 1/4 (Offsite-box SB 11, Folder 1-4)
    - BCL vol. 02 A 1/2 (Offsite-box SB 12, Folder 1-4)
    - BCL Vol. 02 A 1/2 (Offsite-box SB 13, Folder 5-8)
    - BCL Vol. 02 A 3/4 (Offsite-box SB 14, Folder 1-4)
  - BUILDINGS
    - A-C, BCL Vol. 02 B (Offsite-box SB 15, Folder 1-5)
    - D-H, BCL Vol. 02 C (Offsite-box SB 16, Folder 1-4)
    - I-R, BCL Vol. 02 D (Offsite-box SB 17, Folder 1-4)
    - S-Z, BCL Vol. 02 E (Offsite-box SB 18, Folder 1-4)
  - BUSINESS
    - BCL Vol. 02 (Offsite-box SB 19, Folder 1-4)
    - BCL Vol. 02 (Offsite-box SB 20, Folder 5-8)
    - BCL Vol. 02-1/2 (Offsite-box SB 21, Folder 1-4)
    - BCL Vol. 02-1/2 (Offsite-box SB 22, Folder 5-8)
  - CLOTHING (including Ladies, Men's, Millinery, and Shoes)
    - Ladies-General-BCL vol. 03 (Offsite-box SB 23, Folder 1-5)
    - Ladies-General-BCL vol. 03 1/2 (Offsite-box SB 24, Folder 1-2)
    - Ladies-General-BCL vol. 03 1/2 (Offsite-box SB 25, Folder 3-4)
    - Corsets-BCL vol. 03 A (Offsite-box SB 26, Folder 1-5)
    - Haberdashers-BCL vol. 03 G (Offsite-box SB 27, Folder 1-4)
    - Men's-General A-F, BCL vol. 03 H (Offsite-box SB 28, Folder 1-4)
    - Men's-General G-L, BCL vol. 03 I (Offsite-box SB 29, Folder 1-4)
    - Men's-General M-Sl, BCL vol. 03 J (Offsite-box SB 30, Folder 1-4)
    - Men's-General Sm-Z, BCL vol. 03 K (Offsite-box SB 31, Folder 1-4)
    - Millinery, hosiery, hats and caps A-Q, BCL vol. 03 B (Offsite-box SB 32, Folder 1-4)
    - Millinery, hosiery, hats and caps R-Z, BCL vol. 03 C (Offsite-box SB 33, Folder 1-4)
    - Shoes A-F, BCL vol. 03 D (Offsite-box SB 34, Folder 1-5)
    - Shoes G-R, BCL vol. 03 E (Offsite-box SB 35, Folder 1-4)
    - Shoes S-Z, BCL vol. 03 F (Offsite-box SB 36, Folder 1-4)
  - CLUBS and SOCIETIES
    - BCL vol. 04 (Offsite-box SB 37, Folder 1-2)
    - BCL vol. 04 (Offsite-box SB 38, Folder 3-4)
  - COTTON
    - BCL vol. 05 (Offsite-box SB 39, Folder 1-4)
  - DANCES and BALLS
    - BCL vol. 04-1/2 (Offsite-box SB 40, Folder 1-3)
  - DRY GOODS (including Merchants and Textile labels)
    - Merchants A-C, BCL vol. 05 A (Offsite-box SB 41, Folder 1-3)
    - Merchants A-C, BCL vol. 05 A (Offsite-box SB 42, Folder 4-5)
    - Merchants D-Go, BCL vol. 05 B (Offsite-box SB 43, Folder 1-5)
    - Merchants Gr-K, BCL vol. 05 C (Offsite-box SB 44, Folder 1-4)
    - Merchants L-O, BCL vol. 05 D (Offsite-box SB 45, Folder 1-4)
    - Merchants P-Sh, BCL vol. 05 E (Offsite-box SB 46, Folder 1-4)
    - Merchants Si-Z, BCL vol. 05 F (Offsite-box SB 47, Folder 1-2)
    - Merchants Si-Z, BCL vol. 05 F (Offsite-box SB 48, Folder 3-5)
    - Textile labels, BCL vol. 05-1/2 (Offsite-box SB 49, Folder 1-3)
  - ELECTRICITY
    - BCL vol. 06 (Offsite-box SB 50, Folder 1-3)
    - BCL vol. 06 (Offsite-box SB 51, Folder 4-6)
  - FOOD
    - A-Bl, BCL vol. 06 A (Offsite-box SB 52, Folder 1-3)
    - A-Bl, BCL vol. 06 A (Offsite-box SB 53, Folder 4-5)
    - Bo-C, BCL vol. 06 B (Offsite-box SB 54, Folder 1-2)
    - Bo-C, BCL vol. 06 B (Offsite-box SB 55, Folder 3-5)
    - D-F, BCL vol. 06 C (Offsite-box SB 56, Folder 1-4)
    - G-Gw, BCL vol. 06 D (Offsite-box SB 57, Folder 1-4)
    - H-Ke, BCL vol. 06 E (Offsite-box SB 58, Folder 1-4)
    - Ki-Me, BCL vol. 06 F (Offsite-box SB 59, Folder 1-4)
    - Mi-Pr, BCL vol. 06 G (Offsite-box SB 60, Folder 1-4)
    - Pu-S, BCL vol. 06 H (Offsite-box SB 61, Folder 1-2)
    - Pu-S, BCL vol. 06 H (Offsite-box SB 62, Folder 3-4)
    - Sugar, BCL vol. 06 J (Offsite-box SB 63, Folder 1-4)
    - T-Z, BCL vol. 06 I (Offsite-box SB 64, Folder 1-4)
    - Topps Chewing Gum, BCL vol. 06 I-1/2 (Offsite-box SB 65, Folder 1-3)
  - FURNITURE
    - BCL vol. 06 K (Offsite-box SB 66, Folder 1-5)
    - BCL vol. 06 L (Offsite-box SB 67, Folder 1-4)
  - HARDWARE (including machinery, metals, mining, safes, locks)
    - BCL vol. 07 (Offsite-box SB 68, Folder 1-3)
    - BCL vol. 07 (Offsite-box SB 69, Folder 4-6)
    - BCL vol. 07 A (Offsite-box SB 70, Folder 1-4)
    - BCL vol. 07 A-1/2 (Offsite-box SB 71, Folder 1-3)
    - BCL vol. 07 A-1/2 (Offsite-box SB 72, Folder 4-7)
  - HOTELS and RESTAURANTS
    - A-C, BCL vol. 07 B (Offsite-box SB 73, Folder 1-3)
    - A-C, BCL vol. 07 B (Offsite-box SB 74, Folder 4-5)
    - D-Ho, BCL vol. 07 C (Offsite-box SB 75, Folder 1-3)
    - D-Ho, BCL vol. 07 C (Offsite-box SB 76, Folder 4-5)
    - Hu-M, BCL vol. 07 D (Offsite-box SB 77, Folder 1-2)
    - Hu-M, BCL vol. 07 D (Offsite-box SB 78, Folder 3-4)
    - N-P, BCL vol. 07 E (Offsite-box SB 79, Folder 1-4)
    - Q-T, BCL vol. 07 F (Offsite-box SB 80, Folder 1-2)
    - Q-T, BCL vol. 07 F (Offsite-box SB 81, Folder 3-4)
    - U-Z, BCL vol. 07 G (Offsite-box SB 82, Folder 1-3)
  - HOUSEHOLD
    - Ammonia, BCL vol. 09 (Offsite-box SB 83, Folder 1)
    - Carpets, BCL vol. 09 (Offsite-box SB 83, Folder 2)
    - Carpets, Picture frames, BCL vol. 09 (Offsite-box SB 83, Folder 3)
    - Picture frames, BCL vol. 09 (Offsite-box SB 83, Folder 4-5)
    - China and glass, BCL vol. 08 (Offsite-box SB 84, Folder 1-4)
    - Glue, cement, miscellaneous, BCL vol. 09 A (Offsite-box SB 85, Folder 1-5)
    - Lamps and lighting, BCL vol. 08 A (Offsite-box SB 86, Folder 1-4)
    - Laundry, BCL vol. 08 B (Offsite-box SB 87, Folder 1-5)
    - Soap and Candles, BCL vol. 08 C (Offsite-box SB 88, Folder 1-2)
    - Soap and Candles, BCL vol. 08 C (Offsite-box SB 89, Folder 3-4)
    - Matches, polishes, twine, refrigerators, BCL vol. 09 B (Offsite-box SB 90, Folder 1-3)
  - INSURANCE
    - A-Ha, BCL vol. 09 C (Offsite-box SB 91, Folder 1-4)
    - He-N, BCL vol. 09 D (Offsite-box SB 92, Folder 1-4)
    - O-Z, BCL vol. 09 E (Offsite-box SB 93, Folder 1-4)
  - JEWELRY
    - BCL vol. 09 F (Offsite-box SB 94, Folder 1-5)
    - BCL vol. 09 G (Offsite-box SB 95, Folder 1-4)
  - LEATHER GOODS
    - BCL vol. 10 (Offsite-box SB 96, Folder 1-4)
  - LOTTERIES (arranged by state)
    - Foreign, Arkansas, Carolinas, California, Colorado (Offsite-box SB 97, Folder 1)
    - Connecticut (Offsite-box SB 97, Folder 2)
    - Delaware (Offsite-box SB 97, Folder 3-7)
    - District of Columbia (Offsite-box SB 98, Folder 8)
    - Florida, Georgia, Iowa, Kansas (Offsite-box SB 98, Folder 9)
    - Kentucky (Offsite-box SB 98, Folder 10-12)
    - Louisiana (Offsite-box SB 98, Folder 13-16)
    - Maine (Offsite-box SB 99, Folder 17)
    - Maryland (Offsite-box SB 99, Folder 18-24)
    - Massachusetts (Offsite-box SB 100, Folder 25)
    - Missouri, Nebraska, New Hampshire, New Jersey (Offsite-box SB 100, Folder 26)
    - New York (Offsite-box SB 100, Folder 27-30)
    - Ohio (Offsite-box SB 100, Folder 31)
    - Pennsylvania (Offsite-box SB 101, Folder 32-34)
    - Rhode Island (Offsite-box SB 101, Folder 35)
    - Texas (Offsite-box SB 101, Box 36)
    - Vermont (Offsite-box SB 101, Folder 37)
    - Virginia (Offsite-box SB 101, Folder 38)
    - Wyoming (Offsite-box SB 101, Folder 39)
  - MILITARY
    - BCL vol. 10-1/2 (Offsite-box SB 102, Folder 1-2)
    - BCL vol. 10-1/2 (Offsite-box SB 103, Folder 3-4)
  - OIL
    - BCL vol. 10 A (Offsite-box SB 104, Folder 1-3)
  - OPTICAL
    - BCL vol. 10 A-1/2 (Offsite-box SB 105, Folder 1-3)
  - PACKAGING
    - BCL vol. 10 C (Offsite-box SB 106, Folder 1-4)
  - PAPER
    - BCL vol. 11 B (Offsite-box SB 107, Folder 1-2)
    - BCL vol. 11 B (Offsite-box SB 108, Folder 3-4)
  - PERIODICALS
    - BCL vol. 11 (Offsite-box SB 109, Folder 1-5)
    - BCL vol. 11 A (Offsite-box SB 110, Folder 1-6)
  - PHOTOGRAPHY
    - BCL vol. 11 C (Offsite-box SB 111, Folder 1-2)
    - BCL vol. 11 C (Offsite-box SB 112, Folder 3-4)
  - PLASTICS
    - BCL vol. 10 B (Offsite-box SB 113, Box 1-3)
  - PRINTING and ENGRAVING
    - A-H, BCL vol. 13 (Offsite-box SB 114, Folder 1-3)
    - A-H, BCL vol. 13 (Offsite-box SB 115, Folder 4-5)
    - I-Q, BCL vol. 13 A (Offsite-box SB 116, Folder 1-4)
    - R-Z, BCL vol. 13 B (Offsite-box SB 117, Folder 1-4)
    - Modern material, BCL vol. 13 B-1/4 (Offsite-box SB 118, Folder 1-3)
  - PROFESSIONS and OCCUPATIONS
    - Medical, BCL vol. 14 (Offsite-box SB 119, Folder 1-4)
    - Merchants, teachers, trade unions, etc., BCL vol. 14-1/4 (Offsite-box SB 120, Folder 1-3)
  - PUBLICATIONS
    - BCL vol. 12 (Offsite-box SB 121, Folder 1-3)
    - BCL vol. 12 (Offsite-box SB 122, Folder 4-5)
    - BCL vol. 12 A (Offsite-box SB 123, Folder 1-4)
    - BCL vol. 12 B (Offsite-box SB 124, Folder 1-4)
  - RADIUM, URANIUM, etc.
    - BCL vol. 14 A-1/2 (Offsite-box SB 125, Folder 1-4)
  - REAL ESTATE
    - BCL vol. 14 A (Offsite-box SB 126, Folder 1-4)
    - BCL vol. 14 A (Offsite-box SB 127, Folder 5-7)
  - RELIGION, PHILANTHROPY, and HOSPITALS
    - BCL vol. 14 B (Offsite-box SB 128, Folder 1-3)
    - BCL vol. 14 B (Offsite-box SB 129, Folder 4-5)
  - RUBBER
    - BCL vol. 14-1/2 (Offsite-box SB 130, Folder 1-2)
  - SCHOOLS and COLLEGES
    - BCL vol. 14 C (Offsite-box SB 131, Folder 1-2)
    - BCL vol. 14 C (Offsite-box SB 132, Folder 3-4)
    - BCL vol. 14 C-1/2 (Offsite-box SB 133, Folder 1-2)
  - SEEDS and PLANTS
    - BCL vol. 14 D (Offsite-box SB 134, Folder 1-3)
    - BCL vol. 14 D (Offsite-box SB 135, Folder 4-6)
  - SEWING MACHINES
    - BCL vol. 14 E (Offsite-box SB 136, Folder 1-4)
  - SPORTS, TOYS, and GAMES
    - BCL vol. 15 (Offsite-box SB 137, Folder 1-4)
    - BCL vol. 15 A (Offsite-box SB 138, Folder 1-2)
    - BCL vol. 15 A (Offsite-box SB 139, Folder 3-4)
    - BCL vol. 15 A-1/2 (Offsite-box SB 140, Folder 1-4)
  - STATIONERY and VALENTINES
    - BCL vol. 15 B (Offsite-box SB 141, Folder 1-3)
    - BCL vol. 15 B (Offsite-box SB 142, Folder 4-6)
    - BCL vol. 15 C (Offsite-box SB 143, Folder 1-2)
    - BCL vol. 15 C (Offsite-box SB 144, Folder 3-4)
  - STOVES, FURNACES and RANGES
    - A-S, BCL vol. 15 D (Offsite-box SB 145, Folder 1-5)
    - T-Z, BCL vol. 15 E (Offsite-box SB 146, Folder 1-4)
  - THEATRICAL ENTERPRISES (including Theatre, Motion pictures, Musical instruments, Fairs and expositions, Musicals, Lectures, Radio and television, Dance, Music, Skating)
    - Theatre, BCL vol. 16 (Offsite-box SB 147, Folder 1-5)
    - Theatre, BCL vol. 16 A (Offsite-box SB 148, Box 1-5)
    - Motion pictures, BCL vol. 16 B (Offsite-box SB 149, Folder 1-5)
    - Motion pictures, BCL vol. 16 B-1/2 (Offsite-box SB 150, Folder 1-3)
    - Motion pictures, BCL vol. 16 B-3/4 (Offsite-box SB 151, Folder 1-4)
    - Musical instruments, BCL vol. 16 C (Offsite-box SB 152, Folder 1-5)
    - Theatre, fairs and expositions, musicals, musical instruments, and lectures, BCL vol. 16 D (Offsite-box SB 153, Box 1-4)
    - Theatre, fairs and expositions, musicals, musical instruments, and lectures, BCL vol. 16 E (Offsite-box SB 154, Folder 1-5)
    - Theatre, fairs and expositions, musicals, musical instruments, and lectures, BCL vol. 16 F (Offsite-box SB 155, Folder 1-4)
    - Theatre, fairs and expositions, musicals, musical instruments, and lectures, BCL vol. 16 G (Offsite-box SB 156, Folder 1-2)
    - Theatre, fairs and expositions, musicals, musical instruments, and lectures, BCL vol. 16 G (Offsite-box SB 157, Folder 3-4)
    - Theatre, fairs and expositions, musicals, musical instruments, and lectures, BCL vol. 16 H (Offsite-box SB 158, Folder 1-2)
    - Theatre, fairs and expositions, musicals, musical instruments, and lectures, BCL vol. 16 H (Offsite-box SB 159, Folder 3-4)
    - Radio and television, BCL vol. 16 I (Offsite-box SB 160, Folder 1-2)
    - Radio and television, BCL vol. 16 I (Offsite-box SB 161, Folder 3-4)
    - Dance, BCL vol. 16 K (Offsite-box SB 162, Folder 1-2)
    - Dance, BCL vol. 16 K (Offsite-box SB 163, Folder 3-4)
    - Music, BCL vol. 16 L (Offsite-box SB 164, Folder 1-2)
    - Music, BCL vol. 16 L (Offsite-box SB 165, Folder 3-4)
    - Skating, dance, fairs and expositions, BCL vol. 16 M (Offsite-box SB 166, Folder 1-3)
  - TOBACCO
    - BCL vol. 17 (Offsite-box SB 167, Folder 1-2)
    - BCL vol. 17 A (Offsite-box SB 168, Folder 1-2)
    - BCL vol. 17 A (Offsite-box SB 169, Folder 3-4)
    - BCL vol. 17 B (Offsite-box SB 170, Folder 1-4)
    - BCL vol. 17 C (Offsite-box SB 171, Folder 1-4)
    - BCL vol. 17 D (Offsite-box SB 172, Folder 1-4)
  - TOILET ARTICLES and BEAUTY AIDS
    - BCL vol. 18 (Offsite-box SB 173, Folder 1-5)
    - BCL vol. 18 A (Offsite-box SB 174, Folder 1-3)
  - TRANSPORTATION
    - Automobiles, buses, taxis, etc. BCL vol. 19 (Offsite-box SB 175, Folder 1-3)
    - Automobiles, buses, taxis, etc. BCL vol. 19 (Offsite-box SB 176, Folder 4-5)
    - Automobiles, buses, taxis, etc. BCL vol. 19 (Offsite-box SB 177, Folder 6-8)
    - Aviation BCL vol. 19 G (Offsite-box SB 178, Folder 1-3)
    - Aviation BCL vol. 19 G-1/2 (Offsite-box SB 179, Folder 1-2)
    - Bridges, canals, Civil War, ferries, and local transit tickets and passes A-N, BCL vol. 19 B (Offsite-box SB 180, Folder 1-4)
    - Local transit tickets and passes O-Z, BCL vol. 19 C (Offsite-box SB 181, Folder 1-2)
    - Carriages BCL vol. 19 D (Offsite-box SB 182, Folder 1-3)
    - Express companies BCL vol. 19 F (Offsite-box SB 183, Folder 1-2)
    - Railroads BCL vol. 19 A (Offsite-box SB 184, Folder 1-2)
    - Railroads BCL vol. 19 A (Offsite-box SB 185, Folder 3-4)
    - Railroads BCL vol. 19 A-1/2 (Offsite-box SB 186, Folder 1-2)
    - Railroads BCL vol. 19 A-1/2 (Offsite-box SB 187, Folder 3-4)
    - Railroads BCL vol. 19 A-3/4 (Offsite-box SB 188, Folder 3-4)
    - Ships BCL vol. 19 E (Offsite-box SB 189, Folder 1-4)
    - Ships BCL vol. 19 E-1/2 (Offsite-box SB 190, Folder 1-3)
    - Ships BCL vol. 19 E-3/4 (Offsite-box SB 191, Folder 1-2)
    - Ships BCL vol. 19 E-3/4 (Offsite-box SB 192, Folder 3-4)
  - UNDERTAKERS, CEMETERIES, COFFIN MAKERS, and FUNERALS
    - BCL vol. 20 (Offsite-box SB 193, Box SB 193, Folder 1-2)
  - UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT (including Lawyers and Suffrage)
    - BCL vol. 20 A (Offsite-box SB 194, Folder 1-3)
    - BCL vol. 20 A (Offsite-box SB 195, Folder 4-5)
    - BCL vol. 20 B (Offsite-box SB 196, Folder 1-4)
  - WAREHOUSES and WATERWORKS
    - BCL vol. 20 (Offsite-box SB 193, Box 193, Folder 3)
  - WOOL
    - BCL vol. 20 (Offsite-box SB 193, Folder 4)
  - WORLD WAR I
    - War letters, 1917-1919, bound vol. 1 (BCL vol. 23.1) (Offsite-box SB 232, Box SB 197)
    - War letters, 1917-1919, bound vol. 2 (BCL vol. 23.1) (Offsite-box SB 232, Box SB 198)
    - BCL vol. 23.2 (Offsite-box SB 199, Folder 1-9)
  - WORLD WAR II
    - 1939-1940, BCL vol. 23.3 (Offsite-box SB 233, Box SB 200, Folder 1-5)
    - 1940-1941, BCL vol. 23.4 (Offsite-box SB 233, Box SB 201, Folder 1-7)